okay so we have seen that
we have to worry about the read after
right dependencies because we actually
have to feed the value that the
instruction needs from a previous
instruction we also have to worry about
write after write dependencies possibly
because we don't want we want the last
instruction in the program order to be
the last one to actually write the
result and also anti-dependencies we
need to worry about them too because we
don't want to overwrite results before
the instructions that need them had had
a chance to use them
so now we're going to talk about
removing false dependencies
what are false dependencies well we have
read after write we have write after
read and we can also have a write after
a write these
are called true dependencies
because you actually have to obey them
that's how the program computes some
instructions produce values that are
then used by other instructions and so
on so the instructions that use values
really depend on instructions that
previously wrote the results
in contrast
these
are called
false
or name
dependencies
why
well because there is nothing
fundamental about them they are
dependencies just because we are using
the same register for two different
results so for example in a right after
right dependence we have seen that two
different instructions would write to
the same register and that creates the
right after eye dependence if the second
of those two instructions
we're using another register to write
this value
then there would not be no dependence we
will see an example of this a little bit
later
but
the idea is that while true dependencies
you actually
have to delay instructions in order to
satisfy them with the name dependencies
you could actually execute instructions
earlier if only you could take care of
you know kind of multiple values for the
same register as we will see just in
case just in a couple of seconds